# Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer (Bilingual)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

To view this detailed CV, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf</a>

To view my concise Resume, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf</a>

Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer by passion and profession, with years of experience in websites, web apps, and web services development. Working mainly with the Javascript ecosystem (specializing in Node.js Backend Development), and focusing on delivering high quality solutions by following as many web development best practices as possible. Always excited about learning new and developing current soft and technical skills, both on the professional and personal levels.

# Work Expertise

The development stack actively used is focused mainly on the Javascript ecosystem, the main technologies used are:

• Programming languages: Typescript

• Backend: **Node.js** - **Express.js** -

NestJS

• Databases: Prisma - MongoDB - MySQL

• Frontend: React.js

• Testing: **Jest** 

API Architectures: REST API
 Version control: Git - GitHub

# Work Experience

<u>Intermediate Backend Javascript Developer @Combyne Ag | Remote, Canada</u> [MAR 2023 - MAR 2024] Combyne Ag (Acquired by BAYER) is a crop marketing management app that empowers farmers to make quick and easy grain marketing decisions, with all their information in the palm of their hands.

Combyne Connect - product of Combyne - is an API ecosystem that farmers are able to use to connect Combyne to both their farm tools and buyer tools, and to bring their relevant crop marketing data all together in a single place.

Being part of the Combyne Connect Team, as an Intermediate Backend Javascript Developer, my duties were

- With the help of 2 teammates, build Combyne Connect API from scratch using NestJS
- Write unit, integration and e2e tests using Jest for Combyne Connect API
- Write Swagger documentation for Combyne Connect API
- Participate in writing "black box" automated test using Mocha and Chai for Combyne Connect API

#### While working at Combyne Ag, the key achievements were

✔ Build from scratch and deploy the first version of Combyne Connect API

#### Main technologies used at Combyne Ag

Typescript · Node.js · NestJS · Prisma · AWS Cognito · Swagger · Jest · Jira · REST API · Git · GitHub · VSCode · Postman · Slack · MacOS

# Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer (Bilingual)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

To view this detailed CV, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf</a>

To view my concise Resume, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf</a>

### <u>Fullstack Web Developer @YASSIR (YC W20) | Remote, Algeria</u> [MAR 2022 - FEB 2023]

YASSIR is the leading super App for on-demand and payment services in French-Speaking Africa, offers on-demand services such as ride-hailing, last-mile delivery, and financial services to help users pay, save and borrow digitally.

# Being part of the Shared and Financial Services Engineering Team, as a Fullstack Developer doing backend development, the duties were

- Develop new features and fix bugs on the "Referral" project
- Write documentation to help new developers integrate quicker into the team
- Coordinate with the Engineering Manager and Product Managers to agree upon project's specifications
- Write automated tests for the REST API using Postman
- Participate in the recruitment process of new developers by technically interviewing them

#### While working at YASSIR (YC W20), the key achievements were

- ✔ Push the "Referral" project's advancement status from 50% to 80% completion
- ✓ Successfully hire 3 Node.js backend developers

#### Main technologies used at YASSIR (YC W20)

Typescript · Node.js · Express.js · MongoDB · Mongoose.js · Swagger · Jira · REST API · Git · GitHub · VSCode · Postman · Slack · MacOS

#### 

Data Impact is A powerful, collaborative analytics platform that helps brands interpret and master their omnichannel data. Real-time e-store data and advanced A.I. algorithms offer actionable insights and clear strategic guidance for optimized execution across an organization.

#### Being part of the Engineering team, the duties were

- Maintain a proper execution of the data analytics dashboard
- Work with legacy Javascript code
- Hunt and fix bugs, clean the code
- Coordinate with Product Owners
- Help Product Owners detect bugs
- Participate in releases to the pre-production and production environments
- Coordinate with other teams such as PHP and GO developers about data transfer
- Participate in recruiting new developers

#### While working at Data Impact, the key achievement were

- ✓ Detect a hidden bug messing up the dashboard's calculations, and fix it
- ✓ Successfully hire 1 Javascript developer

#### Main technologies used at Data Impact

Javascript ES6 · VSCode · Jira · Git · BitBucket · Slack

# Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer (Bilingual)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

To view this detailed CV, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf</a>

To view my concise Resume, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf</a>

#### <u>Self-taught MERN Stack Developer @Home</u>

[APR 2020 - SEP 2021]

Upleveling Web Development skills during the Covid-19 pandemic, exploring further Javascript ecosystem and learning the MERN Stack through tutorials and side-projects.

During the lockdown, had the chance to deep dive into the Javascript ecosystem. the key achievements were the development of the following side-projects:

#### ✓ Backend Web Projects (REST APIs)

- Dummy React Conference REST API: built using Node.js, Express.js, JWT, MongoDB, and Mongoose.js
  - Hosted on Render link: <a href="https://dummy-react-conf-server.onrender.com">https://dummy-react-conf-server.onrender.com</a>
  - GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-server">https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-server</a>
- Parking Lot REST API: built using Node.js, Express.js, Typescript, In-Memory Storage, and Jest
  - Hosted on Render link: <a href="https://parking-lot-server.onrender.com">https://parking-lot-server.onrender.com</a>
  - GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/salimdellali/parking-lot-server">https://github.com/salimdellali/parking-lot-server</a>
- Text Storing and Processing REST API: built using Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Mongoose.js
  - Hosted on Render link: <a href="https://text-storing-processing.onrender.com/text">https://text-storing-processing.onrender.com/text</a>
  - Github repo: <a href="https://github.com/salimdellali/text-storing-processing">https://github.com/salimdellali/text-storing-processing</a>

#### ✔ Frontend Web Projects

- Dummy React Conference Dashboard: Built as a Jamstack website using React.js,
   React-router-dom, Redux, Formik, and Material-UI as UI library
  - Live demo link: <a href="https://dummy-react-conf-dashboard.netlify.app">https://dummy-react-conf-dashboard.netlify.app</a>
  - GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-dashboard">https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-dashboard</a>
- Dummy React Conference Website: Built as a Jamstack website using React.js,
   React-router-dom, Formik, and React-bootstrap as UI library
  - Live demo link: <a href="https://dummy-react-conf-website.netlify.app">https://dummy-react-conf-website.netlify.app</a>
  - GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-website">https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-website</a>
- Personal Website & Portfolio: https://salimdellali.netlify.app

#### Main technologies learned

Javascript ES6 · Gulp.js · Npm · MongoDB · Express.js · React.js · Node.js · Mongoose.js · Typescript · Redux · Axios · Sass · React-bootstrap · Material-ui · Styled-components · Git · Github · JWT · Jest · REST API · Postman · WebStorm · VSCode · Netlify · Heroku

# Fullstack Web Developer @Mediafex | On-site, Algeria [FEB 2019 - MAY 2020]

Mediafex is a Communication Consulting and Web Agency founded in 1999 by Mr. Mohamed Boumala, the core activities of Mediafex are graphic design, building search engines about companies, producing advertising products and corporate gifts, producing advertising signages, and providing internet services such as web development and web hosting.

#### As a Fullstack Web Developer, the duties were

- Gathering Mr. Boumala's requirements to build websites and web services
- Coordinating with a graphic designer to create assets for websites development
- Developing websites and web services

# Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer (Bilingual)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

To view this detailed CV, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf</a>

To view my concise Resume, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf</a>

#### While working at Mediafex, the key achievements were

- ✔ Building a presentational website for exposing Mediafex company and its services
- ✔ Build a website with a complex search in large catalogs for Line-x Algeria (Line-x Algeria being a company of waterproofing, thermal insulation and protective coating solutions and services, owned by Mr. Boumala)

#### Main technologies used at Mediafex

HTML5 · CSS3 · Javascript ES5 · PHP · MySQL · Bootstrap · JQuery · FileZilla · CPanel · Git · BitBucket · PhpStorm

<u>Wordpress Web Developer @Feel Safety | On-site, Algeria</u> [OCT 2018 - JAN 2019] Feel Safety is specialized in wholesale distribution of personal protective and fire fighting equipment.

#### As a Wordpress Developer, the duties were

- Build new features for the Feel Safety website : <a href="https://www.feelsafety-dz.com">https://www.feelsafety-dz.com</a> using Wordpress Technology
- Fix bugs, and ensure the proper and smooth execution of the website
- Participate in improving the User Interface and User Experience (UI/UX) of the website
- Populate, update and remove products for the online shop on the website

#### While working at Feel Safety, the key achievements were

✔ Fix bugs and improve the UI/UX of the website

#### **Education**

Masters degree in Software Engineering Equivalency by WES - Canada [SEP 2023]

Masters degree in Software Engineering @USTHB - Algeria [SEP 2015 - JUN 2017]

Bachelor degree in Computer Science @USTHB- Algeria [SEP 2012 - JUN 2015]

#### Certifications & Courses

#### **CELPIP English Exam Certificate**

[NOV 2023]

Speaking: 9, Listening: 10, Reading: 10, Writing: 10

Clean code course By Maximilian Schwarzmülle - <u>Udemy certificate</u> [JUN 2021]

#### Languages

Full professional proficiency in: English and French

Professional proficiency in: Arabic and Russian

# Software Engineer & Typescript Backend Web Developer (Bilingual)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

(438)-773-7407 ■ dellali.salim@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dellalisalim

(https://salimdellali.netlify.app https://github.com/salimdellali

To view this detailed CV, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-CV.pdf</a>

To view my concise Resume, visit: <a href="https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf">https://salimdellali.netlify.app/files/Salim-Dellali-Resume.pdf</a>

# Volunteering experience

#### AIESEC - Local Committee Benak, Algeria

[OCT 2014 - MAY 2018]

AIESEC is a global platform for young people to develop their leadership potential through practical experiences of many kinds, including internships, volunteering opportunities, and more. Founded in 1948, AIESEC is a non-governmental and not-for-profit organization entirely run by youth, for youth.

While a student, had the chance to join AIESEC, one of the largest youth movements in the world. The positions held during the AIESEC journey were: Team Member Designer, Team Member Talent Management (TM) Tracking, Team Leader TM Tracking, AIESEC Products Promoter, TM Department Vice President. Ended my journey by becoming an AIESEC Alumnus.